fubles.com 2015-12-05

# Fubles.com - Take the field!

## Data Controller and Owner

Fubles srl – Via Senato, 20 – 20121 Milan (Italy),  
ict@fubles.com  

## Data Processor

**Giuseppe De Giorgi** \- DGRGPP85H23E506X, available at the Owner address

## Types of Data collected

Among the types of Personal Data that Fubles collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookie, Usage Data, First Name, Last Name, Phone number, Email, Genre, Date of Birth, Password, City and Picture. 

Other Personal Data collected may be described in other sections of this privacy policy or by dedicated explanation text contextually with the Data collection.  
The Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or collected automatically when using Fubles.  
Any use of Cookies - or of other tracking tools - by Fubles or by the owners of third party services used by Fubles, unless stated otherwise, serves to identify Users and remember their preferences, for the sole purpose of providing the service required by the User.  
Failure to provide certain Personal Data may make it impossible for Fubles to provide its services.

The User assumes responsibility for the Personal Data of third parties published or shared through Fubles and declares to have the right to communicate or broadcast them, thus relieving the Data Controller of all responsibility.

## Mode and place of processing the Data

### Method of processing

The Data Controller processes the Data of Users in proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification or unauthorized destruction of the Data.  
The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Data Controller, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of the site (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time.

### Place

The Data is processed at the Data Controller headquarters, unless stated otherwise in the rest of this document.

### Conservation Time

The Data is kept for the time necessary to provide the service requested by the User, or stated by the purposes outlined in this document, and the User can always request the Data Controller for their suspension or removal.

## The use of the collected Data

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Application to provide its services, as well as for the following purposes: Analytics, Interaction with external social networks and platforms, Interaction with support and feedback platforms, Displaying content from external platforms, Contacting the User, Registration and authentication, Access to third party services' accounts and Social features. 

The Personal Data used for each purpose is outlined in the specific sections of this document.

## Facebook permissions asked by Fubles

Fubles may ask some Facebook permissions allowing it to perform actions with the User's Facebook account and to retrieve information, including Personal Data, from it.

For more information about the following permissions, refer to the [Facebook permissions documentation](https://developers.facebook.com/docs/authentication/permissions/) and to the [Facebook privacy policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).

The permissions asked are the following: Access Friend Lists, Basic information, Birthday, Chat, Current City, Email and Publish to the Wall. 

## Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

  * ### Access to third party services' accounts

These services allow Fubles to access Data from your account on a third party service and perform actions with it.  
These services are not activated automatically, but require explicit authorization by the User.

#### Access to the Facebook account (Fubles)

This service allows Fubles to connect with the User's account on the Facebook social network, provided by Facebook Inc.

Permissions asked: Access Friend Lists, Birthday, Chat, Current City, Email and Publish to the Wall. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation.php)

  * ### Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

#### Google Analytics (Google)

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of Fubles, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.  
Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

#### Alexa Metrics (Alexa Internet, Inc.)

Alexa Metrics is an analytics service provided by Alexa Internet, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.alexa.com/help/privacy)

#### Google AdWords conversion tracking (Google)

Google AdWords conversion tracking is an analytics service provided by Google, Inc. that connects data from the Google AdWords advertising network with actions performed on Fubles.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

  * ### Contacting the User

#### Contact form (Fubles)

By filling in the contact form with their Data, the Users authorizes Fubles to use these details to reply to requests for information, quotes or any other kind of request as indicated by the form’s header.

Personal Data collected: Email, First Name, Last Name, Phone number and Various types of Data. 

  * ### Displaying content from external platforms

These services allow you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of Fubles and interact with them.  
If a service of this kind is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when users do not use it.

#### Google Maps widget (Google)

Google Maps is a maps visualization service provided by Google Inc. that allows Fubles to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.it/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

  * ### Interaction with external social networks and platforms

These services allow interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of Fubles.  
The interaction and information obtained by Fubles are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network.  
If a service enabling interaction with social networks is installed it may still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

#### Facebook Like button and social widgets (Facebook)

The Facebook Like button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Facebook social network provided by Facebook Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation.php)

  * ### Interaction with support and feedback platforms

These services allow Users to interact with third party support and feedback platforms directly from the pages of Fubles.  
If one of these services is installed, it may collect browsing and usage data in the pages where it is installed, even if the Users do not actively use the service.

#### Uservoice Widget (User voice)

The Uservoice Widget is a service for interacting with the Uservoice support and feedback platform provided by Uservoice Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.uservoice.com/privacy/)

  * ### Registration and authentication

By registering or authenticating, Users allow Fubles to identify them and give them access to dedicated services.  
Depending on what is described below, third parties may provide registration and authentication services.  
In this case, Fubles will be able to access some Data, stored by these third party services, for registration or identification purposes.

#### Direct registration (Fubles)

The User registers by filling out the registration form and providing the Personal Data directly to Fubles.

Personal Data collected: City, Date of Birth, Email, First Name, Genre, Last Name, Password and Picture. 

#### Facebook Authentication (Facebook)

Facebook Authentication is a registration and authentication service provided by Facebook Inc. and is connected to the Facebook social network.

Personal Data collected: Various types of Data. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.facebook.com/help/?page=229348490415842)

  * ### Social features

#### Public profile (Fubles)

Users may have public profiles that other Users can display. In addition to the Personal Data provided, this profile may contain Users' interactions with Fubles.

Personal Data collected: City, First Name, Last Name and Picture. 

#### Inviting and suggesting friends (Fubles)

Fubles may use the Personal Data provided to allow Users to invite their friends - for example through the address book, if access has been provided - and to suggest friends or connections inside it.

Personal Data collected: Various types of Data. 

## Further information about Personal Data

  * ### Further information on public profiles

In addition to the information already mentioned, Fubles publishes on Users' profile the link of their Facebook profile, if Facebook is connected with the User account. 

## Additional information about Data collection and processing

### Legal Action

The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Data Controller, in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of Fubles or the related services. 

### Additional Information about User's Personal Data

In addition to the information in this privacy policy, Fubles may provide the User with contextual information concerning particular services or the collection and processing of Personal Data. 

### System Logs and Maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, Fubles and any third party services may collect files that record interaction with Fubles (System Logs) or use for this purpose other Personal Data (such as IP Address). 

### Information not contained in this policy

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Data Controller at any time at its contact information. 

### The rights of Users

Users have the right, at any time, to know whether their Personal Data has been stored and can consult the Data Controller to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. Requests should be sent to the Data Controller at the contact information set out above. 

Fubles does not support “do not track” requests.  
To understand if any of the third party services it uses honor the “do not track” requests, please read their privacy policies. 

### Changes to this privacy policy

The Data Controller reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. If a User objects to any of the changes to the Policy, the User must cease using Fubles and can request the Data Controller to erase the Personal Data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current privacy policy applies to all Personal Data the Data Controller has about Users. 

### Information about this privacy policy

The Data Controller is responsible for this privacy policy, prepared starting from the modules provided by Iubenda and hosted on the Iubenda's servers. 

###  Definitions and legal references 

#### Personal Data (or Data)

Any information regarding a natural person, a legal person, an institution or an association, which is, or can be, identified, even indirectly, by reference to any other information, including a personal identification number.

#### Usage Data

Information collected automatically from Fubles (or third party services employed in Fubles ), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use Fubles, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server's answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User's IT environment.

#### User

The individual using Fubles, which must coincide with or be authorized by the Data Subject, to whom the Personal Data refer.

#### Data Subject

The legal or natural person to whom the Personal Data refers to.

#### Data Processor

The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization authorized by the Data Controller to process the Personal Data in compliance with this privacy policy.

#### Data Controller (or Application Owner, or Owner)

The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization with the right, also jointly with another Data Controller, to make decisions regarding the purposes, and the methods of processing of Personal Data and the means used, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of Fubles. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of Fubles.

#### Fubles

The hardware or software tool by which the User Personal Data is collected.

#### Cookie

Small piece of data stored in the User's device.

* * *

#### Legal information

Notice to European Users: this privacy statement has been prepared in fulfillment of the obligations under Art. 10 of EC Directive n. 95/46/EC, and under the provisions of Directive 2002/58/EC, as revised by Directive 2009/136/EC, on the subject of Cookies.

This privacy policy is solely about Fubles.
